GANGAREDDY NACHU

gnachu@horizon.csueastbay.edu | www.linkedin.com/in/gangareddy-nachu-209686142 +1(408)-340-0710 | https://github.com/gangareddynachu

SUMMARY

Graduate Student in Computer Science. Have 3+ years of experience in software development and maintenance with domain exposure in Robotic Process Automation (RPA) and Java. Proficient in Data Structures and Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming and

Design.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science

Jan 2021- May 2022

California State University EastBay | Hayward, California | GPA: 3.837 / 4

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

Sep 2014- Apr 2018

Osmania University | Hyderabad | India | CGPA: 8.31 / 10

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• **Programming Languages:** Java, Python, C, JavaScript

• Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JSON, JavaScript, Node JS, Servlets

• Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Frameworks and API: Python Flask, Spring Boot, REST API's

Proficient tools and topics: Apache Tomcat, Postman, AWS, Google App Engine, Data Structures, CI/CD, Gitlab

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at ServiceNow, Santa Clara, CA, USA

06/06/2022-Present

- Worked as a Software developer in the Engineering team of Field Service Management(FSM).
- Actively participated in Scrum meetings ,worked on developing features like Dispatcher Workspace, Agent Mobile App
- Performed Regression testing, cross-team testing to validate the applications across platforms.
- Worked extensively on Script Includes, Business Rules, REST APIs as part of user story and defect fixes.
- Worked on major performance improvements ,enhanced user experience and accessibility of field service mobile app.
- Worked on Localization(L10n) and Internalization(L10n) of various applications to enhance user experience in multiple languages.
- Used Access Control List(ACl's) on the tables to restrict the data and prevent security attacks by unauthorized users.
- Followed various software engineering design principles to optimize the code and contributed to boost the load time and performance of the application.

Graduate Teaching Assistant at California State University, East Bay, Hayward

01/18/2022-05/04/2022

Worked as a Teaching Assistant for CS 301 Data Structures, CS 421 Operating Systems, CS 611 Theory of Computation courses.

Software Engineer at Accenture, Hyderabad, India

05/18/2018-01/04/2021

- Automated several manual human tasks which are redundant, repetitive and time consuming.
- Experienced in building end-to-end RPA. Used Orchestrator for deployment, management and monitoring of Robots.
- Performed tool evaluation and feasibility to help in selecting suitable automation tools for RPA implementation.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Feedback Forum using Python Flask Framework(Deployed on Heroku)

Spring 2021

- It allows the users to submit the feedback. As soon as the feedback is submitted a token is sent to the email of the user.
- Then the administrator provides the response to feedback which can be viewed by the user later with the help of a token.

Photo Post Advisor (Facebook Developer App deployed on Google App Engine)

Summer 2021

- Developed a web application which analyzes the photos selected from a particular page of users' facebook account using Google Computer Vision API .It gathers the information such as likes count and comments count for each photo and generates the report to the user in the form of two tabs. 1)Categories and 2)Photos.
- With the help of this analysis, users can decide which photo to upload next time.

Covid-19 Tracker Application (Java SpringBoot,BootStrap,HTML,CSS)

Fall 2021

- Created a web application which tracks COVID-19 cases across the globe.
- The real time data of virus is fetched from the GitHub repository(in CSV format). Scheduled the Service using CRON.

End to End Employee Website(AWS EC2,S3,RDS,HTML,CSS)

Fall 2021

• This web application allows to store and retrieve employee information from a database. It is deployed on AWS where EC2 is used for launching instances, S3 bucket for storing images and Relational Database Services (RDS) for connection to databases.